<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
      xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>Blizzard Community Platform API Documentation</title>

    <author>
      <personname><firstname>Nick</firstname><surname>Gerakines</surname></personname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname>Blizzard Entertainment</orgname>
        <address><email>ngerakines@blizzard.com</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <pubdate>6/10/2011</pubdate>

    <abstract>
      <para>This is the documentation for the RESTful APIs exposed through the
      World of Warcraft community site as a service to the World of Warcraft
      community.</para>
    </abstract>
  </info>

  <chapter>
    <title>Features</title>

    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>

      <para>The Blizzard Community Platform API provides a number of resources
      for developers and Wow enthusiasts to gather data about their
      characters, guilds and arena teams. This documentation is primarily for
      developers and third parties.</para>

      <para>Blizzard's epic gaming experiences often take place in game, but
      can lead to rewarding and lasting experiences out of game as well.
      Through exposing key sets of data, we can enable the community to create
      extended communities to continue that epic experience.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>API Features</title>

      <para>The API has a number of features that you, as a developer, should
      be aware of.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Access and Regions</title>

        <para>To access the API, HTTP requests can be made to specific urls
        and resources exposed on the regional battle.net domains.</para>

        <example>
          <title>An example request</title>

          <programlisting>GET /api/wow/realm/status HTTP/1.1
Host: us.battle.net
&lt;http headers&gt;</programlisting>
        </example>

        <example>
          <title>An example response</title>

          <programlisting>HTTP/1.1 200 OK
&lt;http headers&gt;

{"realms":[ ... ]}</programlisting>
        </example>

        <para>The regions where this API is available are:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>us.battle.net</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>eu.battle.net</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>kr.battle.net</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>tw.battle.net</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>battlenet.com.cn</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>

        <para>The data available through the API is limited to the region that
        it is in. Hence, US APIs accessed through us.battle.net will only
        contain data within US battlegroups and realms and supports the
        locales of the us.battle.net/wow community site.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>REST</title>

        <para>The API is <emphasis>mostly</emphasis> restful. Data is exposed
        in the form of URIs that represent resources and can be fetched with
        HTTP clients (like web browsers). At this time, the entirety of the
        API is limited to read-only operations.<remark>I'm not terribly
        pleased with this section. Things we should probably also reference
        include any quirks or behaviors that are un-rest-like.</remark></para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Authentication</title>

        <para>API authentication describes how applications will be asked to
        use an identification and signing process to access the API.</para>

        <para>Explain the backstory of application identification and
        authentication.</para>

        <para>List and describe the perks of opting into this process.</para>

        <para>Describe the signing process and the changes in how API requests
        are crafted and made.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Formats and Protocols</title>

        <para>While giving a history of what formats and protocols were
        supported, list those that are supported now.</para>

        <para>Explain what JSON is and how JSONP can be used.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Cached Data and Availability</title>

        <para>Explain that not all data is immediately available. Explain that
        we don’t serve requests asking for data that isn’t immediately
        available.</para>

        <para>Provide an example of the request-reject process and what
        try-again means.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>APIs</title>

    <para>The following sections document the actual API resources and how
    they are used.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Characters</title>

      <para>Character APIs currently provide character profile
      information.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Profile API</title>

        <para>The character profile API is the primary way to access character
        information.</para>

        <para>Introduction to the resource.</para>

        <para>URL structure and components</para>

        <para>Required fields</para>

        <para>Optional Fields</para>

        <para>Field definitions</para>

        <para>Example request</para>

        <para>Example response</para>

        <para>Response description</para>

        <para>Response fields</para>

        <para>Error handling</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Guilds</title>

      <para>Guild APIs currently provide guild profile information.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Realms</title>

      <para>Realm APIs currently provide realm status information.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Static Data</title>

      <para>The static data APIs provide information that can compliment
      profile information to provide structure or definition to the data
      provided.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Character Races</title>

        <para>The character races data API provides a list of character
        races.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Character Classes</title>

        <para>The character classes data API provides a list of character
        classes.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Guild Rewards</title>

        <para>The guild rewards data API provides a list of all guild
        rewards.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Guild Perks</title>

        <para>The guild perks data API provides a list of all guild
        perks.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Policies and Best Practices</title>

    <para>This chapter will outline API policies and best practices when
    interacting with the API.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Caching</title>

      <para>Caching policies should be used by client developers and API
      consumers.</para>

      <para>Provide some example caching timelines for the documented
      resources.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Throttling</title>

      <para>Explain that throttling should be implemented by API consumers and
      why.</para>

      <para>Document the limitations we set on requests.</para>

      <para>Describe what happens when an application crosses the line.</para>

      <para>Example error response</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Support</title>

      <para>Use the forums for your questions and feedback.</para>

      <para>You can also email api-support@blizzard.com for matters that you
      may not want public discussion of</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>
</book>


